

# **ALEXANDRA CANGE**



<u>GitHub</u>



LinkedIn



alexandracange@gmail.com



+33 7 60077179



<u>Portfolio</u>



Wiesbaden, Germany

As an enthusiastic and results-oriented professional with an excitement for data and problem-solving, and with a background in operations, a first short experience in IT and a recent certification in data sciences, I possess a unique blend of analytical, technical, and communication skills. Through my work in various industries and my extensive training in Python, SQL and BI Tools, I have honed my ability to extract meaningful insights from complex data sets and communicate those findings to organisation's all levels stakeholders.

#### **SKILLS**

#### **LANGUAGES**

FRENCH - Native ENGLISH - Fluent GERMAN - Intermediate

#### **TECHNICAL**

CODING

Python, SQL, Javascript, HTML/CSS

**DATA SCIENCES** 

Business Intelligence, Machine Learning, AI, AWS, API, ETL

BUSINESS

Excel, Project Management, Operations, Analytics, SAP S/4HANA

#### **PERSONAL**

FAST LEARNING
ADAPTABILITY
PROBLEM SOLVING
ANALYTICAL MINDSET
COMMUNICATION
CUSTOMERS ORIENTED

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **DATA SCIENCES**

WBS Coding School 09.2022 - 01.2023

- Project Based
- Practice oriented
- Collaborative coding training

## COMMERCE AND INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS

Public University Orléans, France 09.2013 - 07.2016

- Languages
- International Commerce
- International Management

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE:**

• Business Customers Analysis (*Dashboard*)

#### **DEEP LEARNING:**

• Spotify Popularity Prediction (*Presentation*)

#### **MACHINE LEARNING:**

- Playlist Creation (Presentation)
- House Pricing Prediction (Link)
- Movie Recommender (App)

#### **DATA ENGINEERING:**

• E-Scooter Company Advices (Medium Post)

#### **DATA QUALITY:**

• Tech E-Commerce Data (Notebook)

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **JACK WOLFSKIN, IDSTEIN**

IT RETAIL ANALYST

- Ensured user support within the framework of the existing ERP and POS systems-SAP S4 & Advarics
- Administrated, developed and expanded the POS systems and connected systems.
- Supported all value-added processes with the aim of effective and efficient operation and the development of a modern organization.
- Determined requirements in cooperation with the specialist departments regarding extensions and adaptations of the POS systems and organizational processes.
- Actively monitoring data hygiene end to end along interfaces and systems.
- Key contact for departments creating and consuming POS related data. Communication hub for all POS related topics. Solving and delegating issues to responsible stakeholders. Interacting with internal departments and external parties on POS processes and issues.

#### VIU EYEWEAR, MUNICH

#### SENIOR OPERATIONS MANAGER

04.2021 - 05.2022

05.2023 - 07.2023

- Directed and oversaw staff of 25+ employee, designing schedules to meet the needs of the department as well as the needs of employees.
- Implemented a new inventory analysing system resulting saving 20% of spent time.

#### SWQ (Shipping, Warehouse, Quality Control) MANAGER

01.2020 - 03.2021

- Maintained detailed records of stocks, incoming goods and shipments.
- · Evaluated productivity, implemented new processes and tracking processes systems resulting a better organisation and KPIs.

#### SHIPPING SUPERVISOR

**OPERATIONS SPECIALIST** 

01.2019 - 12.2019

Supervised up to 10 shipping employees.
 Focused all outbound orders are processed within 1.5.

• Ensured all outbound orders are processed within 1.5 day.

10.2017 - 12.2018

• Assisted to company goals and operational excellence.

#### KIABI, ORLÉANS

INTERNSHIP ASSISTANT MANAGER

06.2016 - 09.2016

Analysed with Excel and reported on the NPS to management and director.